I'm about to interview one of the richest men in
the entire world, but how did he make his billions?
I sell chicken fingers. So chicken fingers. I do.
Are you a business owner? I am own raising canes
She owed raising canes. Yeah, I founded it
back in 1996. You heard it from him
He's the founder of raising canes you guys, but he's
not rich. He's not even wealthy. No, no, no, no
He's got a net worth of well, I'll
let him tell you that what is your network?
I'm north of 20 billion north of
you said 20 billion 20 billion dollars. Yeah
20 billion dollars you guys with a capital B
So, you know I had to fly out
to where it all started out here Baton Rouge
Louisiana at the original raising canes location to get billionaire secrets
from Todd Graves one of the wealthiest men in the entire world
And I'm gonna be asking him everything in this interview
Me and you died tomorrow and you had
one guiding principle to leave with the younger generation
What would that be nothing is
off the table on this interview?
I'm gonna be getting the exact blueprint
on what he did to become a billionaire
If you had to rebuild a billion dollar
company with three moves, what would they be?
This video is about
To be insane from start to finish to stay tuned until
the end that being said let's get this video on the way
Arch guys, we're in the car had
to interview the billionaire Todd Graves right now
But I gotta point something
out before we do this interview
This is gonna be the 25th billionaire that I've ever interviewed and
you want to know the craziest part as I've interviewed billionaires across
Heck to real estate a law to retail
But never
Have I ever interviewed somebody that got a billionaire rich
from opening up fast food restaurants and selling chicken tenders
So this is gonna be unlike any interview that I've ever done
before and I cannot wait to figure out his secrets to becoming a
Billionaire with that being said let's
go meet Todd arch you guys
So we just got to the og
pains location out here in Baton Rouge, Louisiana
This is where it all started you
guys started here now is over 900 locations
So we're gonna be interviewing him at the og we're gonna
be linking up with him any minute right now for you guys
Come on. How you doing Todd?
Doing great. How you doing?
Great to meet you
How y'all doing? They love your stuff. I
love all of them. It's always in my feed
I didn't know when it pops right up. I think they're
great. I've been looking forward to this for a long time
I really appreciate you coming down to Baton Rouge to do this
and what you got for avid teens people in Austin right here
Oh, yeah, that's great. Well, this is the
mothership man. That's where it all started right here
So we love learning from successful people and we're just super happy
to be here. I appreciate I like how you make it relatable people
Watching it's entertaining. They learn something so it's
great. I have one rule for the video
No holding back you give them the
secrets on what it takes to become rich
Okay, great. Can we make that happen? I can
do that. Let's do that. I'll do my best
Who am I here with today Todd graves founder raising
canes for those who don't know? What is your business?
My business is a chicken fingers
I serve chicken finger meals and great tea and lemonade and
actually do it all over the country in parts of the world
How did you get into the chicken finger
business fight like for those who don't know?
What was that turning point getting into this business? Oh, you
know, I grew up in high school in college working in restaurants
So I really liked it. I was always entrepreneurial
I was the kid that in the neighborhood had
the the lemonade stand and I cut grass for dollars
So just natural thing for me was going to
Own business and then a new
restaurant take you back to college
You had a class where you proposed chicken tenders as a
business idea and you got the lowest grade in the class
I did I did look I presented
the like the Bible on chicken fingers
I worked in the business so I
knew exactly what I needed to do
But the professor gave it the worst grade in
the class because he said the plan was good
But the concept will never work serving just chicken fingers
while other restaurants at the time were adding menu items variety
They're adding healthy items said it would never
work, but you didn't listen to other people
You didn't listen to people that doubted you
Oh, you know what?
If you're an entrepreneur you
use that as fuel when someone
Tells you can't do it you get a chip on
your shoulder. You're like I will show you I'll do it
So let's talk to people right
now that are either doubting themselves
They're facing a lot of rejection
rejections inevitable when we started this channel
I'd go up to people off the street
and I'd get 20 30 rejections in a row
How do you deal with rejection early on before
you had the credibility before you prove the model?
How did you kind of deal with it
and built that mental framework as an entrepreneur?
I use rejection as fuel every time told
me somebody told me hey, this will never work
I was like, you know what?
I'll prove it to you that I will make
it and every time that I started doubting myself
I thought you know what you believe in yourself
and you
Have this dream and you know it'll work so
believe in yourself work hard and make it happen
Tell me the story about how you got the money to start
that first business because the restaurant business it's capital-intensive in today's world
Banks aren't really lending money to restaurants. Maybe they want shoes
to how did you get the money to start your first location?
I got turned on by every banker in town.
So I knew I had to raise my own money
So literally I caught a plane to gang Anchorage, Alaska caught
a float plane to King Salmon, Alaska hitchhike to knack-knack, Alaska
I spent a month on the tundra in a
tent before I got a job commercial fishing in Alaska
But so when you don't have you can't get money
It's very very hard to get
You got to make money yourself and there's
tons of jobs if you're willing to work hard
I don't know if I'd recommend
now someone doing the dangerous jobs
I did like Alaskan fishing but you
can earn money to get in business
And so once you earn enough money yourself,
there's also great programs. The SBA lending is outstanding
The government backs the bank something to like 90%
right so they can be more lenient with the loans
They do to get entrepreneurs like me getting started
other great government agencies like small business development center
That'll help you with advice service core retire executives
I used all these resources
And really learned a lot
to help me start my business
Did you borrow money from
a bank to start your business?
Yeah, once I raised a lot of
my own personal equity about fifty thousand dollars
I was able to go in and get
a small SBA loan for fifty thousand dollars
And I was able to get this old place here dilapidated old
restaurant space and do the work myself and to be opened up in
1996 what did you learn about negotiating with banks?
If you know your numbers you have to know your numbers inside
and out you have to believe in them low mediums and highs
And the low you put on which is break-even
that the business will work on the low end
the
medium projections are I think I'll do
this and we're gonna make good money
And then there's a high projections
look at this thing really kicks off
We're gonna have a lot of good money and we're
gonna be able to pay you back your loan quicker
So somebody who sold billions
of dollars throughout your career
What is your best sales and negotiation
advice for anybody in business best negotiation advice?
I can give anybody is believe in what you're doing and know
your numbers inside now and don't let people talk you down your numbers
If they work they work because if they don't like them that
go to somebody else somebody else eventually will if they don't somebody
Absolutely and I'm living proof of that
What's the most amount of money that you made
in a single year 400 million 400 million dollars?
Yeah, so what is your network? I'm north of 20 billion north
of you said 20 billion 20 billion dollars. Yeah as a billionaire
What's the best financial advice you've
ever received guys listen very carefully?
I built the craziest network in the entire world by the age
of 23 years old and it's the reason why I built a
multi million dollar business before most people graduate
college and I'm not kidding my businesses make over
400 to 600 thousand dollars every single month
and the reason why is because I've connected with
More multi millionaires and more billionaires
than anyone in the entire world
I mean, I'm literally interviewing Todd graves the founder
of raising canes who's worth over 20 billion dollars
And I have these conversations every single week with
multi millionaire and billionaire entrepreneurs, but here's the thing guys
I realized about a year ago that
it shouldn't just be me having these conversations
So I built something insane that has never been
built before and I built it just for you
I built a private community for entrepreneurs and people wanting to
better themselves where I give you guys direct access to the same
multi millionaires
And billionaires that I interview on this channel every single week and
I called it the school of mentors and inside the school of mentors
You're not just watching videos
You're literally hopping on live calls live zoom calls with
eight-figure entrepreneurs nine-figure entrepreneurs billionaires people that built billion dollar companies
Where you ask them your questions directly and get mentored from these
business owners the people that I interview they mentor you every single week
And they give you guys step-by-step playbooks and
the blueprints on sales on marketing on investing
You're even able to book one-on-one calls
With real mentors and we've already
helped over 4,000 entrepreneurs inside the community
So when you join you literally get
access to a network of 4,000 entrepreneurs
Some of these people have already built seven and eight-figure businesses and you
can come learn from a connect with these members and now if you're
Watching this you can join the community the number one community for
business owners in the entire world for less than a dollar a day
It's just $29 a month. It's gonna get you
access to the millionaires and billionaires that I interview
So all you have to do to join now is go down and
click the link in the description of this video to join the group
to join the School of Mentors, the number one community,
the most powerful community for entrepreneurs
in the entire world.
So I can't wait to see you on the inside.
With that being said, let's get back to the interview.
What's the best financial advice you've ever received?
I almost broke our business.
I over levered it.
You know, I was young and I was growing,
over leveraging, taking too much debt on.
I felt 10 feet tall and bulletproof.
And then when Hurricane Katrina
hit, we were in a bind.
I had 21 to 28 restaurants go down.
I had to pay the banks.
I was in a bad bind.
We reopened quickly, thank goodness, and go.
But since that day, I've never over leveraged our business.
I don't take on too much debt.
I grow with more equity.
That's a smart thing to do.
How many locations do you have now?
We have over 900 locations in
the US and the Middle East.
Over 900 locations.
Over 900, yeah.
This is the original location right here.
You went from one to
10 to 100 to 900 locations.
What is your secret to scaling a business?
Do one thing and do it better than anybody else.
Focus on that.
Know what you're good at
and execute on a daily basis,
then scale.
What was that one thing that
you did better than anybody else?
That's chicken finger meals, man.
You know, you have to have an amazing,
amazing product and service.
And in restaurants, you have to have
something that's craveable, absolutely craveable.
People think about, they want it often.
If you have a mediocre product, you'll never make it.
And also, too, is where these young entrepreneurs,
they'll start businesses, and then they'll
start branching out in different products and services.
They lose focus of what they're really good at.
Focus on the one thing you do great.
Mine is craveable chicken finger meals.
Yours might be something else.
But stick to it, execute great, and then grow it.
You've had a lot of people telling you that, oh,
you've got to expand the menu.
You've got to diversify.
But you know that if
you focus on that one thing
and do it better than anybody else,
it'll take care of itself.
Yeah, absolutely.
If you try to be all things to all people,
you don't satisfy anybody.
Do what people love and do it exceptionally well,
day in, day out.
You own over 90% of Cades.
I do, yeah.
What percentage of Cades do you own?
91%, 92%, something like that.
So how important is it to maintain ownership and equity
in the business?
If you take on owners in your business,
investors that are sophisticated,
they might have different intentions than you do, right?
All I have to listen to
is my crew and my customers.
And so since I own the business, I
get to make the right
decisions based on the long-term success
of the business.
So for example, if it's a bad year,
let's say, say, I'm going to be a salesman.
Sales aren't as high as they should be.
Let's say food cost goes up.
I don't have to make short-term decisions
to do short-term gains.
I don't have to lower wages.
I don't have to raise prices.
I can do the right decisions, stick to what
I'm doing for long-term success.
Now, there's a lot of chicken finger restaurants.
Have you ever been afraid of competition?
You know what?
I love competition, man.
It fuels you up, you know?
So I love it.
I love it when competition goes out there.
This is the United States, man.
I mean, more people that come up
and try to do what I'm doing,
go for it.
But you better be ready, because
no one's going to outwork me.
No one's going to care about their crew more.
And you know what?
Keep going, because I get fired up
when I hear of another competitor coming up
and grazing up, because I'm going
to do our job that much better.
But you're worth over $20 billion.
Are you still motivated to keep on going?
Man, like day one, for
me, this is a purpose-driven business.
What I can do with hiring
people and having a great place
to work and what I can do for the money
I can give back to communities,
that for me just drives me.
Having purpose is what's important.
I think when you start
your business, you have this dream.
And that dream for me was
to have a great place serving
great chicken and people enjoying themselves, right?
Have a great place for people to work.
But as you get older and mature, and you
get into your business, you go, you
start realizing you have a purpose.
And my purpose was hiring great people in
and having a great job.
My purpose was being able
to take money that we make
and give it back to the communities.
And that's what drives me every morning.
So you never got complacent?
Never got complacent, never will.
Why not?
Because I have this great purpose, right?
And so right now, if I'm worth $20 billion,
most of that money is going
to go back to help people.
What if I can turn that into $40?
What if I can turn that into $60?
What if my kids can turn
it into hundreds of billions of dollars?
That can really help people out there.
It's safe to say that you're not thinking of days.
You're thinking of decades.
You think very long term.
Yeah, I'm actually thinking next generation.
How do we keep this going?
And how do we continue to help people?
See, me and my family, we believe people
aren't here to serve us.
We're here to serve them.
And by scaling the business
and growing and doing these things,
we can do really big impact someday.
To lead is to serve.
Yeah, absolutely, 100%.
Give me your best leadership advice for anybody in business
right now, because leadership is the downfall of even some
of the biggest companies in the world.
What's your best leadership advice
to somebody who's the number
one of their company right now?
Lead by example and lead
people by their hearts and minds.
They see me in working in the restaurants.
They know I'm working late at night.
They know I'm always taking care
of my crew, so they work hard for me.
And that's why we have such great customer service.
Believe in people.
Take care of people.
That's the best way to lead.
Have you ever been fucked over in business?
Oh, man.
I mean, look, people come and go.
I mean, for everything from contractors
that don't do what they're supposed to do, everybody
else, but you learn from that and you move on.
Look, I think you learn more from your mistakes
than you do from your successes.
And we're constantly getting knocked back.
There's some bad people out there
that want to take advantage of you.
Surround yourself by good people.
Trust, but verify.
And if they screw you over, then move on.
Don't do business with them anymore.
I'm going to challenge you, right?
Take me back.
What was the most life-changing, pivotal conversation
you've had?
One of my mentors told me once, Todd,
concentrate more on progress rather than perfection.
I want to do everything so perfect.
Let's say it's a new training manual.
I wouldn't release it because
I kept just whiting it out
and trying to make it perfect.
I was halting progress in the business.
Think about it as progress.
That one training program can be version one.
You can be on version 100 a year from now,
but don't halt your progress just
because you want it to
be perfect because it's your baby.
If you lost everything tomorrow,
could you make it all back?
Absolutely, I could.
Yeah, absolutely.
If everything lost in this,
I would stick to the restaurant
business because I know it.
I think it's important to stick to what you know.
But I'd look for another craveable product.
I'd look at something I could focus on
and I could build a team around to focus on,
and then I'd scale it.
Do you believe in God?
I do believe in God.
Look, I think God made me good at chicken fingers
to help people, right?
And so that's my purpose.
So if you were to teach a master class,
give me a lesson about business right here
that is not taught in school.
You have to have a great product or service
to be good in business to make money, right?
To sustain it.
The most important thing is,
are you ready to do it?
I tell young entrepreneurs, think
how hard it is to start your business
and then multiply that by infinity.
And if you're still committed to it,
then you could be a success.
You don't have quality of life when
you're starting a business.
The workload is amazing.
The risk tolerance has to be very high.
It's very risky of just your time
and the money you put into it.
Other people invest in your business.
It's a risk for them.
There's a lot of pressure that goes with it.
But if you're able to withstand it,
then you will be successful.
So many amazing business ideas came up
that stopped because they gave up.
My best advice I can
give a young entrepreneur when they're
getting started is never, ever, ever, ever, ever give up.
Believe in yourself and make it happen.
Do you think everybody's built for entrepreneurship?
I don't think everybody's cut out to be an entrepreneur.
You have to have a high risk tolerance.
You have to be able to give up, work-life balance.
You have to work just
insane hours and keep yourself going.
And it's OK if you're not.
But you have to be committed
to that kind of crazy life
if you want to actually be an entrepreneur.
I had a quote that got me through.
Actually, it's my quote.
It's like, nothing ever happens unless somebody
pursues a vision fanatically.
You have to be a fanatic.
Fanaticism is what will get you through.
What do billionaires do differently from millionaires?
The only difference between millionaire business owners
and billionaire business owners?
Millionaires are scale.
It's just that want to grow, growing like crazy.
Because million dollar businesses are great.
You've done the hard part.
Grow it and scale it, and you'll become a billionaire.
And don't give up.
And never, ever, ever give up.
How old are you now?
I'm 53 now.
Tom, me and you die tomorrow, and you
had one guiding principle to lead with the younger
generation, what would that be?
My advice to people would be, be good to people
and leave this world better than you found it.
You've got amazing advice, sir.
Thank you so much for your time.
Man, I appreciate it.
I got to get some chicken tenders, though.
Hell yeah, you do.
This is a mothership.
You've got to eat here, man.
This is where it all started.
This is a meal from the mothership,
with a sweet tea or lemonade?
I'm a sweet tea guy.
Yeah, me too.
I'm a sweet tea guy, too.
Way back to your sauce, right?
Yeah, let's check it out.
Here's the box combo.
This is it right here.
This is it.
Same thing.
This is the quality right here.
Nothing's changed on this menu for 29 years.
Yep.
Real good.
I still eat it all the time.
How did you come up with the sauce right here?
Well, let me tell you.
But you know.
The old adage there.
You don't have to kill you.
Uh-huh.
Yep.
Here's the secret.
Just me and the dog, though.
We make it fresh in-house at all of our restaurants.
So we have components you put together,
but spice packs and different things that go in it,
nobody knows what that is.
So people get close.
Love to see it on social media.
People do the recipe, and I'm
like, eh, you missed a few things.
A lot of restaurant owners,
they struggle with margins, right?
In the food business.
How have you overcome that?
It's really tough, man.
There's margins in all volume.
Margins for us is very tight,
which is between $0.05 and $0.10
on a dollar if you're doing really well.
And so you have to do that with sales.
So for us, we do large
volumes because we make such small margins.
So it's push the top line, push the top line,
and be smart with the bottom line.
But always better quality, better service,
even if it costs you more,
pays off in the end.
So one of our values is
sales driven, but still being profit smart,
but be sales driven.
Right.
All right, you guys.
That's a wrap on today's
video with the legend, Todd Graves,
the founder of Raising Cane's Chicken.
First of all, this is fire, but I need everybody
to like and subscribe for amazing
content we've got coming every week.
Because I'm going all over the world
to bring you guys the biggest business
owners.
Just like Todd.
Graves.
Everybody go down and click the
link in the description of this video
to join the School of Mentors,
the number one community for business
owners in the entire world, where
we give you guys direct access
to the people we interview every week on live call.
So we can't wait to see you on the inside.
With that being said, see you in the next video.